{
  "category_1": [
    {
      "question": "Which Death Eater's trial does Harry see when he first looks into Dumbledore's Pensieve?",
      "answer": "Igor Karkaroff's",
      "key_words": ["Death Eater", "trial", "Pensieve", "Igor Karkaroff"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who sacrifices his piece during the giant wizard chess game so Harry can win and stop Lord Voldemort from reaching the Sorcerer's Stone?",
      "answer": "Ron Weasley",
      "key_words": ["chess", "sacrifice", "Ron Weasley", "Sorcerer's Stone"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In what type of container is Lord Voldemort reborn?",
      "answer": "A giant cauldron",
      "key_words": ["Voldemort", "reborn", "cauldron"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell conjures the Dark Mark?",
      "answer": "Morsmordre",
      "key_words": ["Dark Mark", "spell", "Morsmordre"]
    },
    {
      "question": "At the start of their sixth year at Hogwarts, which schoolmate is Harry convinced has become a Death Eater?",
      "answer": "Draco Malfoy",
      "key_words": ["sixth year", "Death Eater", "Draco Malfoy"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Death Eater is imprisoned in Azkaban after Sirius Black's death?",
      "answer": "Lucius Malfoy",
      "key_words": ["Death Eater", "Azkaban", "Lucius Malfoy"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who confiscates the locket Horcrux from Mundungus Fletcher?",
      "answer": "Dolores Umbridge",
      "key_words": [
        "Horcrux",
        "locket",
        "Mundungus Fletcher",
        "Dolores Umbridge"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of Muggle structure in London do the Death Eaters cause to collapse?",
      "answer": "A bridge",
      "key_words": ["Muggle", "London", "bridge", "collapse", "Death Eaters"]
    },
    {
      "question": "As they prepare to head home after their fifth year at school, what does Harry tell Ron and Hermione they have that Lord Voldemort doesn't?",
      "answer": "Something worth fighting for",
      "key_words": [
        "Harry Potter",
        "Voldemort",
        "fifth year",
        "worth fighting for"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who does Igor Karkaroff say is a spy in the Department of Mysteries?",
      "answer": "Augustus Rookwood",
      "key_words": [
        "Igor Karkaroff",
        "spy",
        "Department of Mysteries",
        "Rookwood"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Harry use to destroy the diadem of Rowena Ravenclaw?",
      "answer": "A Basilisk fang",
      "key_words": [
        "Harry Potter",
        "destroy",
        "diadem",
        "Ravenclaw",
        "Basilisk fang"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Professor Snape's first name?",
      "answer": "Severus",
      "key_words": ["Professor Snape", "first name", "Severus"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the derogatory term Draco Malfoy uses to describe Muggle-born wizards?",
      "answer": "Mudblood",
      "key_words": ["Draco Malfoy", "Muggle-born", "insult", "Mudblood"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the derogatory term Draco Malfoy uses to describe Muggle-born wizards?",
      "answer": "Mudblood",
      "key_words": ["Draco Malfoy", "insult", "Muggle-born", "Mudblood"]
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Mr. Weasley, Sirius Black has escaped from Azkaban to kill whom?",
      "answer": "Harry Potter",
      "key_words": ["harry", "potter", "boy who lived", "chosen one"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What Ministry initiative is Dolores Umbridge in charge of after the Death Eaters take control?",
      "answer": "The Muggle-born Registration Commission",
      "key_words": [
        "muggle-born",
        "muggles",
        "muggle",
        "registration",
        "commission",
        "muggleborn",
        "mudblood"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is sent to Azkaban under suspicion of reopening the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "Hagrid",
      "key_words": [
        "hagrid",
        "rubeus hagrid",
        "keeper of keys",
        "groundskeeper"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How does Harry open the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "By speaking Parseltongue",
      "key_words": [
        "parseltongue",
        "snake language",
        "speaking to snakes",
        "snake speak",
        "parselmouth"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who do Harry and Hermione discover hidden in Bathilda Bagshot's skin in her home at Godric's Hollow?",
      "answer": "Nagini",
      "key_words": [
        "nagini",
        "snake",
        "voldemort's snake",
        "horcrux",
        "serpent"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Avada Kedavra is known as which curse?",
      "answer": "The Killing Curse",
      "key_words": [
        "killing curse",
        "death curse",
        "unforgivable curse",
        "avada kedavra",
        "murder curse"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What name forms the anagram 'I am Lord Voldemort'?",
      "answer": "Tom Marvolo Riddle",
      "key_words": [
        "tom riddle",
        "tom marvolo riddle",
        "voldemort",
        "he who must not be named"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the heir of Slytherin?",
      "answer": "Tom Riddle/Lord Voldemort",
      "key_words": [
        "tom riddle",
        "voldemort",
        "lord voldemort",
        "heir",
        "slytherin heir"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which ingredients does Snape find missing from his stores during Harry's fourth year at Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Boomslang Skin and Lacewing Flies",
      "key_words": [
        "boomslang",
        "lacewing",
        "flies",
        "skin",
        "potion ingredients"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the incantation for the Stunning Spell?",
      "answer": "Stupefy",
      "key_words": ["stupefy", "stunning spell", "stunning curse", "stun"]
    },
    {
      "question": "How high were the highest constructed magical walls of the maze in the third task of the Triwizard Tournament?",
      "answer": "40 feet high",
      "key_words": [
        "40 feet",
        "forty feet",
        "maze",
        "triwizard",
        "tournament",
        "third task",
        "walls"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to Ron when Disapparating from the Ministry of Magic?",
      "answer": "He gets Splinched",
      "key_words": [
        "splinched",
        "splinching",
        "disapparating",
        "apparition",
        "teleporting",
        "split apart"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which spell produces light from the end of a wand?",
      "answer": "Lumos",
      "key_words": [
        "lumos",
        "light spell",
        "illumination",
        "wand light",
        "bright spell"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Hermione smell when she encounters the potion Amortentia?",
      "answer": "Freshly mown grass, new parchment and spearmint toothpaste",
      "key_words": [
        "grass",
        "parchment",
        "toothpaste",
        "spearmint",
        "mown grass",
        "fresh grass",
        "new parchment",
        "love potion",
        "amortentia"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to the photos of Hermione in her parents' home when she uses the Obliviate charm on them?",
      "answer": "Her image disappears",
      "key_words": [
        "disappears",
        "vanishes",
        "fades",
        "image disappears",
        "photos",
        "pictures",
        "obliviate",
        "memory charm"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which spell does Harry use on the Gringotts goblin who doubts the identity of Hermione as Bellatrix Lestrange?",
      "answer": "Imperio/the Imperius Curse",
      "key_words": [
        "imperio",
        "imperius",
        "imperius curse",
        "unforgivable curse",
        "mind control",
        "control curse"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who signs a note left inside the fake locket Horcrux?",
      "answer": "R.A.B (Regulus Arcturus Black)",
      "key_words": [
        "r.a.b",
        "rab",
        "regulus",
        "regulus black",
        "regulus arcturus black",
        "sirius brother"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What breaks Harry's wand?",
      "answer": "A rebounding curse",
      "key_words": [
        "rebounding curse",
        "rebound",
        "curse",
        "backfire",
        "reflected spell"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who destroys the locket Horcrux?",
      "answer": "Ron Weasley",
      "key_words": [
        "ron",
        "ron weasley",
        "ronald",
        "ronald weasley",
        "weasley",
        "gryffindor sword"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Professor Lupin say the appearance of the Boggart as a Dementor indicates is Harry's greatest fear?",
      "answer": "Fear itself",
      "key_words": [
        "fear itself",
        "fear",
        "boggart",
        "dementor",
        "greatest fear",
        "lupin"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who sets Hagrid's hut on fire after Dumbledore has been killed?",
      "answer": "Bellatrix Lestrange",
      "key_words": [
        "bellatrix",
        "bellatrix lestrange",
        "lestrange",
        "bella",
        "death eater"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who kills Professor Dumbledore?",
      "answer": "Professor Snape",
      "key_words": [
        "snape",
        "severus snape",
        "professor snape",
        "severus",
        "potions master"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use against the Hungarian Horntail in the Triwizard Tournament?",
      "answer": "Accio",
      "key_words": [
        "accio",
        "summoning charm",
        "summoning spell",
        "firebolt",
        "broomstick"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who breaks Harry's nose on the Hogwarts Express?",
      "answer": "Draco Malfoy",
      "key_words": ["draco", "draco malfoy", "malfoy", "slytherin", "ferret"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use against the Dementors in the underpass?",
      "answer": "Expecto Patronum",
      "key_words": [
        "expecto patronum",
        "patronus",
        "patronus charm",
        "stag",
        "dementors"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the prophecy say Harry has the power to do?",
      "answer": "Vanquish the Dark Lord",
      "key_words": [
        "vanquish",
        "defeat",
        "dark lord",
        "voldemort",
        "prophecy",
        "destroy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What shape is Harry's Patronus?",
      "answer": "A stag",
      "key_words": ["stag", "deer", "prongs", "james potter", "father"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who saves Harry from drowning when he retrieves the sword of Gryffindor?",
      "answer": "Ron Weasley",
      "key_words": [
        "ron",
        "ron weasley",
        "ronald",
        "weasley",
        "ginger",
        "red hair"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which professor teaches Astronomy at Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Professor Sinistra",
      "key_words": [
        "sinistra",
        "professor sinistra",
        "astronomy",
        "stars",
        "planets"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What charm does Flitwick teach Harry's year in their first Charms lesson?",
      "answer": "Wingardium Leviosa",
      "key_words": [
        "wingardium leviosa",
        "levitation",
        "floating",
        "feather",
        "flitwick"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "category_2": [
    {
      "question": "Who retrieves the sword of Gryffindor from the lake?",
      "answer": "Harry (with the help of Ron)",
      "key_words": ["sword of Gryffindor", "lake", "Harry", "Ron"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these was NOT an option on the Weasleys' magical clock that indicated each family member's location: Home, Dentist, Prison or Forbidden Forest?",
      "answer": "Forbidden Forest",
      "key_words": ["Weasleys' clock", "Forbidden Forest", "locations"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Rita Skeeter use to write her interviews?",
      "answer": "A Quick-Quotes Quill",
      "key_words": ["Rita Skeeter", "interviews", "Quick-Quotes Quill"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the trophy awarded to the winner of the Triwizard Tournament?",
      "answer": "The Triwizard Cup",
      "key_words": ["Triwizard Tournament", "trophy", "Triwizard Cup"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What shoes do the Weasley twins sell in their shop that allow people to walk up walls?",
      "answer": "Sticky Trainers",
      "key_words": ["Weasley twins", "shop", "Sticky Trainers", "walk up walls"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What store in Diagon Alley has three Quaffles hanging from its sign?",
      "answer": "Quality Quidditch Supplies",
      "key_words": [
        "Diagon Alley",
        "store",
        "Quaffle",
        "Quality Quidditch Supplies"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In a house in Budleigh Babberton, Dumbledore discovers a Muggle magazine containing what that Dumbledore loves?",
      "answer": "Knitting patterns",
      "key_words": [
        "Budleigh Babberton",
        "Dumbledore",
        "Muggle magazine",
        "knitting patterns"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Ron use to destroy the Horcrux locket?",
      "answer": "The sword of Gryffindor",
      "key_words": ["Ron Weasley", "Horcrux", "locket", "sword of Gryffindor"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What Muggle perfume billboard does Dumbledore appear in front of when he meets Harry in the London Underground?",
      "answer": "Divine Magic",
      "key_words": ["Muggle", "perfume billboard", "Dumbledore", "Divine Magic"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Muggle waitress in the underground diner see the pictures do in Harry's copy of the Daily Prophet?",
      "answer": "Move",
      "key_words": [
        "Muggle waitress",
        "underground diner",
        "Daily Prophet",
        "pictures move"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What book does Mad-Eye Moody give Neville Longbottom?",
      "answer": "Magical Water Plants of the Highland Lochs",
      "key_words": ["Mad-Eye Moody", "Neville Longbottom", "book"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Horace Slughorn disguised as when Harry first meets him?",
      "answer": "An armchair",
      "key_words": ["Horace Slughorn", "disguised", "armchair"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the final fate of the Sorcerer's Stone?",
      "answer": "It's destroyed",
      "key_words": ["Sorcerer's Stone", "destroyed"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In his youth, what kind of Bertie Bott's Every-Flavor Bean did Dumbledore unfortunately eat?",
      "answer": "Vomit-flavored",
      "key_words": ["Dumbledore", "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "vomit"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In his youth, what kind of Bertie Bott's Every-Flavor Bean did Dumbledore unfortunately eat?",
      "answer": "Vomit-flavored",
      "key_words": ["Dumbledore", "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "vomit"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who owned the Invisibility Cloak prior to Harry?",
      "answer": "His father",
      "key_words": ["father", "james potter", "james", "dad", "his dad"]
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Professor Dumbledore, what kind of object can conceal a Horcrux?",
      "answer": "Any object",
      "key_words": ["any object", "anything", "any", "object", "horcrux"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of flying car do the Weasleys own?",
      "answer": "Ford Anglia",
      "key_words": ["ford anglia", "ford", "anglia", "blue car", "flying car"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What date does Tom Riddle's diary show Harry?",
      "answer": "June 13th",
      "key_words": [
        "june 13",
        "june 13th",
        "13 june",
        "13th june",
        "thirteenth",
        "diary date"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What headline does Harry read in a newspaper on the Knight Bus?",
      "answer": "Escape from Azkaban!",
      "key_words": [
        "escape from azkaban",
        "azkaban escape",
        "sirius escape",
        "newspaper headline",
        "knight bus"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does Grindelwald tell Lord Voldemort the Elder Wand is?",
      "answer": "Dumbledore's grave",
      "key_words": [
        "dumbledore's grave",
        "dumbledores grave",
        "grave",
        "tomb",
        "burial site",
        "graveyard"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does the Sorting Hat reside when not in use?",
      "answer": "Dumbledore's office",
      "key_words": [
        "dumbledore's office",
        "dumbledores office",
        "headmaster's office",
        "headmasters office",
        "office"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Ron and Harry hide Crabbe and Goyle while they impersonate the two Slytherins?",
      "answer": "In a broom closet",
      "key_words": [
        "broom closet",
        "closet",
        "cupboard",
        "storage room",
        "crabbe",
        "goyle",
        "polyjuice"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is Moaning Myrtle sitting in the plumbing when someone throws a book through her head?",
      "answer": "The U-bend",
      "key_words": [
        "u-bend",
        "u bend",
        "pipe",
        "plumbing",
        "toilet",
        "myrtle",
        "moaning myrtle"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where, in Hogwarts, is the Ravenclaw diadem Horcrux hidden?",
      "answer": "The Room of Requirement",
      "key_words": [
        "room of requirement",
        "come and go room",
        "diadem",
        "ravenclaw diadem",
        "horcrux"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In what room did Lavender realize Ron cared for Hermione?",
      "answer": "Hospital wing",
      "key_words": [
        "hospital wing",
        "infirmary",
        "medical wing",
        "lavender",
        "lavender brown",
        "ron",
        "hermione"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which classroom at Hogwarts is populated with crystal balls?",
      "answer": "Divination",
      "key_words": [
        "divination",
        "divination classroom",
        "crystal balls",
        "trelawney",
        "fortune telling"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which classroom does Hermione storm out of in her third year at Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Divination",
      "key_words": [
        "divination",
        "divination classroom",
        "hermione",
        "trelawney",
        "third year"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What time does the Hogwarts Express leave King's Cross Station on the first day of term?",
      "answer": "11:00 AM",
      "key_words": [
        "11:00 am",
        "11 am",
        "eleven",
        "eleven o'clock",
        "hogwarts express",
        "kings cross"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What store sells wizard equipment in Diagon Alley?",
      "answer": "Wiseacre's Wizarding Equipment",
      "key_words": [
        "wiseacre's",
        "wiseacres",
        "wizarding equipment",
        "diagon alley",
        "wizard equipment"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What book with a yellow cover is in Umbridge's desk drawer at the Ministry of Magic?",
      "answer": "Mudbloods and How to Spot Them",
      "key_words": [
        "mudbloods and how to spot them",
        "yellow book",
        "umbridge",
        "ministry",
        "desk drawer"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does the Basilisk's fang injure Harry?",
      "answer": "On his arm",
      "key_words": [
        "arm",
        "his arm",
        "basilisk fang",
        "poison",
        "venom",
        "injury"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What store in Diagon Alley sells twine and rope?",
      "answer": "Peter Boat",
      "key_words": ["peter boat", "twine", "rope", "diagon alley", "store"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What shop in Diagon Alley sells cauldrons?",
      "answer": "Potage's Cauldron Shop",
      "key_words": [
        "potage's",
        "potages",
        "cauldron shop",
        "cauldrons",
        "diagon alley"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What village near Hogwarts do students visit on weekends?",
      "answer": "Hogsmeade",
      "key_words": [
        "hogsmeade",
        "hogsmeade village",
        "village",
        "weekends",
        "students"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the pub at Hogsmeade?",
      "answer": "The Three Broomsticks",
      "key_words": [
        "three broomsticks",
        "pub",
        "hogsmeade",
        "madam rosmerta",
        "bar"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Harry and Cho have their first kiss?",
      "answer": "The Room of Requirement",
      "key_words": [
        "room of requirement",
        "come and go room",
        "harry",
        "cho",
        "cho chang",
        "first kiss"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do the Hogwarts house-elves work?",
      "answer": "The kitchens",
      "key_words": [
        "kitchens",
        "kitchen",
        "house-elves",
        "house elves",
        "dobby",
        "winky"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does Professor Umbridge force Harry to write lines with a Blood Quill?",
      "answer": "Her office",
      "key_words": [
        "her office",
        "umbridge office",
        "blood quill",
        "detention",
        "lines",
        "writing"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What location serves as the headquarters of the Order of the Phoenix?",
      "answer": "12 Grimmauld Place",
      "key_words": [
        "12 grimmauld place",
        "grimmauld place",
        "number twelve",
        "order headquarters",
        "sirius house"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Harry and Hermione camp when they are on the run during Deathly Hallows?",
      "answer": "Various forests in Britain",
      "key_words": [
        "forests",
        "britain",
        "various forests",
        "camping",
        "on the run",
        "deathly hallows"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Harry and Ginny share their first kiss?",
      "answer": "The Gryffindor common room",
      "key_words": [
        "gryffindor common room",
        "common room",
        "harry",
        "ginny",
        "ginny weasley",
        "first kiss"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "category_3": [
    {
      "question": "What creature does Harry see in the shadows just before the Knight Bus arrives?",
      "answer": "A giant dog",
      "key_words": ["Harry", "shadows", "Knight Bus", "giant dog"]
    },
    {
      "question": "To which Hogwarts house do Harry, Ron, and Hermione all belong?",
      "answer": "Gryffindor",
      "key_words": ["Hogwarts house", "Harry", "Ron", "Hermione", "Gryffindor"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Harry's owl?",
      "answer": "Hedwig",
      "key_words": ["Harry", "owl", "Hedwig"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In Harry's first year at Hogwarts, what is the name of the centaur who saves him from Lord Voldemort in the Forbidden Forest?",
      "answer": "Firenze",
      "key_words": [
        "Harry",
        "first year",
        "centaur",
        "Firenze",
        "Forbidden Forest"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What small creature does Ginny Weasley get from her brothers' shop?",
      "answer": "A Pygmy Puff",
      "key_words": ["Ginny Weasley", "Pygmy Puff", "Weasley shop"]
    },
    {
      "question": "According to director Christopher Columbus, what type of animal's facial characteristics did they give to centaurs to make them more powerful looking?",
      "answer": "A horse",
      "key_words": [
        "Christopher Columbus",
        "centaurs",
        "facial characteristics",
        "horse"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of blood drips from the ceiling of the house where Slughorn is hiding?",
      "answer": "Dragon's blood",
      "key_words": ["Slughorn", "hiding", "ceiling", "dragon's blood"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who let the troll into Hogwarts castle during the Hallowe'en feast?",
      "answer": "Professor Quirrell",
      "key_words": ["troll", "Hogwarts", "Hallowe'en feast", "Quirrell"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What giant creature of fire does Lord Voldemort conjure to attack Dumbledore during their duel?",
      "answer": "A snake",
      "key_words": ["Voldemort", "duel", "Dumbledore", "snake", "fire"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who suggests using Thestrals to fly to London to save Sirius Black?",
      "answer": "Luna Lovegood",
      "key_words": [
        "Thestrals",
        "fly",
        "London",
        "Sirius Black",
        "Luna Lovegood"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What animal drags Ron into the tunnel at the base of the Whomping Willow?",
      "answer": "A dog (Sirius Black's Animagus form)",
      "key_words": [
        "Ron Weasley",
        "Whomping Willow",
        "tunnel",
        "Sirius Black",
        "Animagus",
        "dog"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What should you never do to a Hippogriff as they are very proud creatures?",
      "answer": "Insult them",
      "key_words": ["Hippogriff", "insult", "proud creatures"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Dobby feels so bad about sending the Bludger after Harry that he does what to his hands?",
      "answer": "He irons them",
      "key_words": ["Dobby", "Bludger", "punishment", "hands", "iron"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for someone who can speak to snakes?",
      "answer": "Parselmouth",
      "key_words": ["speak to snakes", "Parselmouth"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for someone who can speak to snakes?",
      "answer": "Parselmouth",
      "key_words": ["speak to snakes", "Parselmouth"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which owl gets lost delivering Hagrid's release papers?",
      "answer": "Errol",
      "key_words": [
        "errol",
        "owl",
        "hagrid",
        "release papers",
        "weasley owl",
        "lost"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which beloved pet is killed during Harry's escape from Privet Drive with the Order of the Phoenix?",
      "answer": "Hedwig",
      "key_words": [
        "hedwig",
        "owl",
        "harry's owl",
        "snowy owl",
        "pet",
        "killed",
        "privet drive"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of creature is Fawkes?",
      "answer": "A Phoenix",
      "key_words": [
        "phoenix",
        "fawkes",
        "dumbledore's phoenix",
        "fire bird",
        "immortal bird"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who blinds the Basilisk in the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "Fawkes the phoenix",
      "key_words": [
        "fawkes",
        "phoenix",
        "basilisk",
        "blinds",
        "chamber of secrets",
        "eyes"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of creature is the Basilisk lurking in the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "A serpent",
      "key_words": [
        "serpent",
        "snake",
        "basilisk",
        "giant snake",
        "chamber of secrets"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Harry speaks Parseltongue to a snake to prevent an attack on which student during Duelling Club?",
      "answer": "Justin Finch-Fletchley",
      "key_words": [
        "justin finch-fletchley",
        "justin",
        "finch-fletchley",
        "parseltongue",
        "duelling club",
        "snake"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is speculated to be the informant leaking Dumbledore's secrets in Rita Skeeter's book?",
      "answer": "Bathilda Bagshot",
      "key_words": [
        "bathilda bagshot",
        "bagshot",
        "rita skeeter",
        "informant",
        "dumbledore",
        "secrets"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who does Harry impersonate with Polyjuice Potion his second year at school?",
      "answer": "Gregory Goyle",
      "key_words": [
        "gregory goyle",
        "goyle",
        "polyjuice potion",
        "impersonate",
        "second year"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who does Hermione impersonate using Polyjuice Potion when she, Ron, Harry, and Griphook break into Gringotts?",
      "answer": "Bellatrix Lestrange",
      "key_words": [
        "bellatrix lestrange",
        "bellatrix",
        "lestrange",
        "hermione",
        "polyjuice",
        "gringotts"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Viktor Krum is selected by the Goblet of Fire as the Triwizard champion for which school?",
      "answer": "Durmstrang",
      "key_words": [
        "durmstrang",
        "viktor krum",
        "krum",
        "goblet of fire",
        "triwizard",
        "champion"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which characters did twins Oliver and Jamie Phelps portray?",
      "answer": "Fred and George Weasley",
      "key_words": [
        "fred and george weasley",
        "fred",
        "george",
        "weasley twins",
        "oliver phelps",
        "jamie phelps"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the only one of the three brothers from The Tale of the Three Brothers to voluntarily present himself to Death during old age?",
      "answer": "The third/the youngest",
      "key_words": [
        "third brother",
        "youngest",
        "youngest brother",
        "three brothers",
        "death",
        "deathly hallows"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the headmistress of Beauxbatons Academy of Magic?",
      "answer": "Madame Maxime",
      "key_words": [
        "madame maxime",
        "maxime",
        "beauxbatons",
        "headmistress",
        "olympe maxime"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of Harry's friends did Matthew Lewis play?",
      "answer": "Neville Longbottom",
      "key_words": [
        "neville longbottom",
        "neville",
        "longbottom",
        "matthew lewis",
        "gryffindor"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the name of the Hippogriff Hagrid introduced to the class during his first lesson?",
      "answer": "Buckbeak",
      "key_words": [
        "buckbeak",
        "hippogriff",
        "hagrid",
        "first lesson",
        "care of magical creatures"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Aunt Muriel, what serious crime did Professor Dumbledore's father commit?",
      "answer": "He killed three Muggles",
      "key_words": [
        "killed three muggles",
        "three muggles",
        "killed 3 muggles",
        "3 muggles",
        "aunt muriel",
        "dumbledore's father",
        "percival dumbledore"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Weasley twin catches Ginny and Harry kissing on the day of Bill and Fleur's wedding?",
      "answer": "George",
      "key_words": [
        "george",
        "george weasley",
        "weasley twin",
        "ginny",
        "harry",
        "wedding",
        "bill",
        "fleur"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Mr. Filch's first name?",
      "answer": "Argus",
      "key_words": ["argus", "filch", "argus filch", "caretaker", "squib"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which student does McGonagall recall has a 'particular proclivity for pyrotechnics'?",
      "answer": "Seamus Finnigan",
      "key_words": [
        "seamus finnigan",
        "seamus",
        "finnigan",
        "mcgonagall",
        "pyrotechnics",
        "explosions"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who punches Draco in the face for his desire to see Buckbeak's execution?",
      "answer": "Hermione Granger",
      "key_words": [
        "hermione granger",
        "hermione",
        "granger",
        "draco",
        "punch",
        "buckbeak",
        "execution"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Hogwarts student does Ariana Dumbledore bring to Harry, Ron, and Hermione through her portrait?",
      "answer": "Neville Longbottom",
      "key_words": [
        "neville longbottom",
        "neville",
        "ariana dumbledore",
        "portrait",
        "room of requirement"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What creature does Harry talk to at the zoo during his visit with the Dursleys?",
      "answer": "A snake",
      "key_words": [
        "snake",
        "serpent",
        "zoo",
        "dursleys",
        "parseltongue",
        "boa constrictor"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is Harry Potter's godfather?",
      "answer": "Sirius Black",
      "key_words": [
        "sirius black",
        "sirius",
        "black",
        "godfather",
        "padfoot",
        "prisoner"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of Hogwarts co-founder Slytherin?",
      "answer": "Salazar",
      "key_words": [
        "salazar",
        "slytherin",
        "salazar slytherin",
        "founder",
        "hogwarts founder"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of Hogwarts co-founder Ravenclaw?",
      "answer": "Rowena",
      "key_words": [
        "rowena",
        "ravenclaw",
        "rowena ravenclaw",
        "founder",
        "hogwarts founder"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of Hogwarts co-founder Hufflepuff?",
      "answer": "Helga",
      "key_words": [
        "helga",
        "hufflepuff",
        "helga hufflepuff",
        "founder",
        "hogwarts founder"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of Hogwarts co-founder Gryffindor?",
      "answer": "Godric",
      "key_words": [
        "godric",
        "gryffindor",
        "godric gryffindor",
        "founder",
        "hogwarts founder"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "category_4": [
    {
      "question": "Gwenog Jones is the captain of which Quidditch team?",
      "answer": "Holyhead Harpies",
      "key_words": ["Gwenog Jones", "Quidditch", "Holyhead Harpies"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Ron's parents go during his first Christmas break at Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Romania",
      "key_words": ["Ron Weasley", "parents", "Christmas break", "Romania"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of Ron's brothers marries Fleur Delacour?",
      "answer": "Bill Weasley",
      "key_words": [
        "Ron Weasley",
        "brother",
        "marriage",
        "Bill Weasley",
        "Fleur Delacour"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Name the 5 members of the Order of the Phoenix that come to the rescue in the Department of Mysteries.",
      "answer": "Sirius Black, Tonks, Kingsley Shacklebolt, Remus Lupin, Mad-Eye Moody",
      "key_words": [
        "Order of the Phoenix",
        "Department of Mysteries",
        "Sirius Black",
        "Tonks",
        "Kingsley Shacklebolt",
        "Remus Lupin",
        "Mad-Eye Moody"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a nickname Bellatrix sometimes calls her sister?",
      "answer": "Cissy",
      "key_words": ["Bellatrix", "nickname", "Cissy", "Narcissa"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What did Albus Dumbledore discover that dragon’s blood could be used as?",
      "answer": "An oven cleaner",
      "key_words": ["Dumbledore", "dragon’s blood", "uses", "oven cleaner"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In what subject does Professor Quirrell claim to have had a yearlong sabbatical before teaching at Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Vampires",
      "key_words": ["Professor Quirrell", "sabbatical", "subject", "vampires"]
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Bellatrix Lestrange, how many Aurors did it take to capture her and send her to Azkaban?",
      "answer": "Six",
      "key_words": [
        "Bellatrix Lestrange",
        "Aurors",
        "Azkaban",
        "capture",
        "six",
        "6",
        "6 aurors",
        "six aurors"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Harry tell Luna Lovegood he is not according to the Quibbler?",
      "answer": "Crazy",
      "key_words": ["Harry Potter", "Luna Lovegood", "Quibbler", "crazy"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What powder must be used for magical travel through fireplaces?",
      "answer": "Floo powder",
      "key_words": ["fireplaces", "magical travel", "Floo powder"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of Hagrid's Care of Magical Creatures classes does Draco Malfoy insult?",
      "answer": "The Hippogriff lesson",
      "key_words": [
        "Hagrid",
        "Care of Magical Creatures",
        "Draco Malfoy",
        "Hippogriff lesson"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of the famous alchemist Flamel?",
      "answer": "Nicolas",
      "key_words": ["alchemist", "Flamel", "Nicolas"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Ron Weasley's house?",
      "answer": "The Burrow",
      "key_words": ["Ron Weasley", "house", "The Burrow"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Ron Weasley's house?",
      "answer": "The Burrow",
      "key_words": ["Ron Weasley", "house", "The Burrow"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the Minister for Magic for the first five years that Harry attends Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Cornelius Fudge",
      "key_words": [
        "cornelius fudge",
        "fudge",
        "minister for magic",
        "minister",
        "five years"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the initials of Harry's oldest son?",
      "answer": "J.S.P.",
      "key_words": [
        "j.s.p.",
        "j s p",
        "james sirius potter",
        "james",
        "oldest son",
        "initials"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of Hogwarts co-founder Gryffindor?",
      "answer": "Godric"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first name of Hogwarts co-founder Hufflepuff?",
      "answer": "Helga"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who sends a message during Bill and Fleur's wedding to warn everyone that the Ministry has fallen?",
      "answer": "Kingsley Shacklebolt",
      "key_words": [
        "kingsley shacklebolt",
        "kingsley",
        "shacklebolt",
        "bill",
        "fleur",
        "wedding",
        "ministry fallen"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of broom does Draco's father give to the Slytherin Quidditch team?",
      "answer": "Nimbus 2001",
      "key_words": [
        "nimbus 2001",
        "nimbus",
        "2001",
        "two thousand one",
        "two thousand and one",
        "draco",
        "lucius malfoy",
        "slytherin",
        "broom"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What breaks Harry's arm during a Quidditch match against Slytherin?",
      "answer": "A rogue Bludger",
      "key_words": [
        "rogue bludger",
        "bludger",
        "harry's arm",
        "arm",
        "quidditch",
        "slytherin"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Fawkes do the first time Harry meets him in Dumbledore's office?",
      "answer": "Bursts into flames",
      "key_words": [
        "bursts into flames",
        "flames",
        "fire",
        "fawkes",
        "phoenix",
        "dumbledore's office",
        "dies",
        "die"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who does Tom Riddle turn in, claiming that person opened the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "Hagrid",
      "key_words": [
        "hagrid",
        "rubeus hagrid",
        "tom riddle",
        "chamber of secrets",
        "framed"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which family does Dobby serve until he is freed?",
      "answer": "The Malfoys",
      "key_words": [
        "malfoys",
        "malfoy family",
        "dobby",
        "house elf",
        "freed",
        "lucius malfoy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the skeletal winged horses that pull the carriages from Hogsmeade to Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Thestrals",
      "key_words": [
        "thestrals",
        "skeletal horses",
        "winged horses",
        "carriages",
        "hogsmeade",
        "death"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the Weasleys' old owl?",
      "answer": "Errol",
      "key_words": ["errol", "weasley owl", "old owl", "weasleys", "grey owl"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Ron's pet rat?",
      "answer": "Scabbers",
      "key_words": [
        "scabbers",
        "rat",
        "ron's rat",
        "peter pettigrew",
        "wormtail"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the Black family house-elf?",
      "answer": "Kreacher",
      "key_words": [
        "kreacher",
        "house-elf",
        "house elf",
        "black family",
        "grimmauld place"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What creatures does Hagrid say are as clever as they come but not the most friendly of beasts?",
      "answer": "Goblins",
      "key_words": [
        "goblins",
        "hagrid",
        "clever",
        "not friendly",
        "beasts",
        "gringotts"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the name of the Hippogriff Hagrid introduced to the class during his first lesson?",
      "answer": "Buckbeak"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Hagrid's half-brother?",
      "answer": "Grawp",
      "key_words": [
        "grawp",
        "hagrid",
        "half-brother",
        "giant",
        "forbidden forest"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does Bellatrix scratch Griphook with her knife?",
      "answer": "His cheek",
      "key_words": [
        "cheek",
        "his cheek",
        "bellatrix",
        "griphook",
        "knife",
        "scratch"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell did Harry use to save himself from falling off his broom in his first Quidditch match?",
      "answer": "Arresto Momentum",
      "key_words": [
        "arresto momentum",
        "falling",
        "broom",
        "first quidditch match",
        "hermione"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Hermione use to free Harry and Ron from the Devil's Snare?",
      "answer": "Lumos Solem",
      "key_words": [
        "lumos solem",
        "devil's snare",
        "devils snare",
        "hermione",
        "light",
        "sun"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion did Harry use to disguise himself as a Slytherin student?",
      "answer": "Polyjuice Potion",
      "key_words": [
        "polyjuice potion",
        "disguise",
        "slytherin",
        "goyle",
        "transformation"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use against the Dementors to conjure a Patronus?",
      "answer": "Expecto Patronum",
      "key_words": [
        "expecto patronum",
        "patronus",
        "dementors",
        "stag",
        "conjure"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use against the Hungarian Horntail in the Triwizard Tournament?",
      "answer": "Accio",
      "key_words": [
        "accio",
        "summoning charm",
        "hungarian horntail",
        "triwizard",
        "firebolt"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell disarms an opponent?",
      "answer": "Expelliarmus",
      "key_words": ["expelliarmus", "disarming", "disarms", "wand", "opponent"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell stuns an opponent?",
      "answer": "Stupefy",
      "key_words": ["stupefy", "stunning", "stuns", "opponent", "unconscious"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell binds a target with ropes?",
      "answer": "Incarcerous",
      "key_words": ["incarcerous", "binds", "ropes", "target", "binding"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell is used to conjure the Dark Mark?",
      "answer": "Morsmordre",
      "key_words": [
        "morsmordre",
        "dark mark",
        "conjure",
        "death eaters",
        "skull"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell repairs broken objects?",
      "answer": "Reparo",
      "key_words": ["reparo", "repairs", "broken", "objects", "fix"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell kills instantly?",
      "answer": "Avada Kedavra",
      "key_words": [
        "avada kedavra",
        "killing curse",
        "instantly",
        "death",
        "unforgivable"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "category_5": [
    {
      "question": "Where does Dumbledore hide the Sorcerer's Stone?",
      "answer": "Inside the Mirror of Erised",
      "key_words": ["Dumbledore", "Sorcerer's Stone", "Mirror of Erised"]
    },
    {
      "question": "How many leeches does the brewing of Polyjuice Potion require?",
      "answer": "12",
      "key_words": [
        "Polyjuice Potion",
        "leeches",
        "brewing",
        "12",
        "twelve",
        "twelve leeches"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do the Weasleys use Omnioculars?",
      "answer": "In the stands at the Quidditch World Cup",
      "key_words": ["Weasleys", "Omnioculars", "Quidditch World Cup"]
    },
    {
      "question": "How many levels does the Knight Bus have?",
      "answer": "Three",
      "key_words": [
        "Knight Bus",
        "levels",
        "three",
        "3",
        "3 levels",
        "three levels"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "At which London railway station does Dumbledore meet Harry?",
      "answer": "Surbiton",
      "key_words": ["Dumbledore", "Harry", "railway station", "Surbiton"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What subject did Horace Slughorn teach at Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Potions",
      "key_words": ["Horace Slughorn", "teaching", "Potions"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which professor tries to prevent Harry Potter from attending Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "Professor Quirrell",
      "key_words": ["Harry Potter", "Hogwarts", "prevent", "Professor Quirrell"]
    },
    {
      "question": "How old was Tom Riddle when he first opened the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "16",
      "key_words": [
        "Tom Riddle",
        "Chamber of Secrets",
        "opened",
        "16 years old",
        "16",
        "sixteen",
        "sixteen years old"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What color were Albus Dumbledore's favorite socks?",
      "answer": "Purple",
      "key_words": ["Albus Dumbledore", "favorite socks", "purple"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who helps Harry, Ron, and Hermione escape from Gringotts on the back of a dragon?",
      "answer": "Griphook",
      "key_words": [
        "Harry Potter",
        "Ron Weasley",
        "Hermione Granger",
        "Gringotts",
        "dragon",
        "Griphook"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which potion grants good luck to the drinker?",
      "answer": "Felix Felicis",
      "key_words": ["potion", "good luck", "Felix Felicis"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Dumbledore's first name?",
      "answer": "Albus",
      "key_words": ["Dumbledore", "first name", "Albus"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Harry Potter's pet owl?",
      "answer": "Hedwig",
      "key_words": ["Harry Potter", "pet owl", "Hedwig"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Harry Potter's pet owl?",
      "answer": "Hedwig",
      "key_words": ["Harry Potter", "pet owl", "Hedwig"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Hermione's Petrified body is found near what area of Hogwarts?",
      "answer": "The library",
      "key_words": ["library", "hermione", "petrified", "body", "hogwarts"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Harry and Dumbledore go to find a Horcrux together?",
      "answer": "The cave",
      "key_words": [
        "cave",
        "the cave",
        "harry",
        "dumbledore",
        "horcrux",
        "locket"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How many years ago did the Hogwarts founders live?",
      "answer": "1000 years",
      "key_words": [
        "1000 years",
        "thousand years",
        "founders",
        "hogwarts founders",
        "1000"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In Harry's second year, what is the password to enter Professor Dumbledore's office?",
      "answer": "\"Sherbet Lemon\"",
      "key_words": [
        "sherbet lemon",
        "password",
        "dumbledore's office",
        "second year",
        "gargoyle"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does Grindelwald tell Lord Voldemort the Elder Wand is?",
      "answer": "Dumbledore's grave",
      "key_words": [
        "dumbledore's grave",
        "dumbledores grave",
        "grave",
        "tomb",
        "burial site",
        "graveyard"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What headline does Harry read in a newspaper on the Knight Bus?",
      "answer": "Escape from Azkaban!",
      "key_words": [
        "escape from azkaban",
        "azkaban escape",
        "sirius escape",
        "newspaper headline",
        "knight bus"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Rather than a ghost, what does Tom Riddle say he is when he meets Harry in the Chamber of Secrets?",
      "answer": "A memory, preserved in a diary for fifty years.",
      "key_words": [
        "memory",
        "preserved",
        "diary",
        "fifty years",
        "50 years",
        "50",
        "tom riddle",
        "chamber of secrets"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "While under Tom Riddle's control, who opened the Chamber of Secrets and wrote threatening messages on the castle walls?",
      "answer": "Ginny Weasley",
      "key_words": [
        "ginny weasley",
        "ginny",
        "tom riddle",
        "chamber of secrets",
        "control",
        "messages"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "On their quest for the Sorcerer's Stone, Harry, Ron, and Hermione need to catch what flying object?",
      "answer": "A key",
      "key_words": [
        "key",
        "flying key",
        "winged key",
        "sorcerer's stone",
        "philosophers stone",
        "catch"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Other than a note, what does Hermione have in her hand when she is found Petrified?",
      "answer": "A mirror",
      "key_words": [
        "mirror",
        "hermione",
        "petrified",
        "hand",
        "note",
        "basilisk"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to ink on the pages of Tom Riddle's diary?",
      "answer": "It disappears",
      "key_words": [
        "disappears",
        "vanishes",
        "ink",
        "tom riddle",
        "diary",
        "pages"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who has bequeathed gifts to Ron, Harry and Hermione that the Minister for Magic personally delivers?",
      "answer": "Albus Dumbledore",
      "key_words": [
        "albus dumbledore",
        "dumbledore",
        "bequeathed",
        "gifts",
        "minister",
        "will"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How is Harry, as Albert Runcorn, able to get into Dolores Umbridge's office without being seen by the numerous personnel outside of it?",
      "answer": "By setting off a Decoy Detonator",
      "key_words": [
        "decoy detonator",
        "albert runcorn",
        "umbridge",
        "office",
        "harry",
        "polyjuice"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What store sells wizard equipment in Diagon Alley?",
      "answer": "Wiseacre's Wizarding Equipment",
      "key_words": [
        "wiseacre's",
        "wiseacres",
        "wizarding equipment",
        "diagon alley",
        "wizard equipment"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What color is the Weasleys' flying car?",
      "answer": "Blue",
      "key_words": [
        "blue",
        "weasley",
        "weasleys",
        "flying car",
        "ford anglia",
        "car"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Ron see when he looks into the Mirror of Erised?",
      "answer": "He is Head Boy and is also holding the Quidditch Cup as Quidditch captain",
      "key_words": [
        "head boy",
        "quidditch cup",
        "captain",
        "mirror of erised",
        "ron",
        "desires"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What name is on the sign of the Broom Brakes Service shop in Diagon Alley?",
      "answer": "Shimmy Hardsteering",
      "key_words": [
        "shimmy hardsteering",
        "broom brakes",
        "service",
        "diagon alley",
        "shop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What store in Diagon Alley sells twine and rope?",
      "answer": "Peter Boat",
      "key_words": ["peter boat", "twine", "rope", "diagon alley", "store"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What can be viewed inside a Pensieve?",
      "answer": "Memories",
      "key_words": ["memories", "pensieve", "viewed", "dumbledore", "thoughts"]
    },
    {
      "question": "How many turns does Dumbledore suggest Hermione give the Time-Turner to go back and save Sirius Black?",
      "answer": "Three",
      "key_words": [
        "three",
        "3",
        "turns",
        "time-turner",
        "time turner",
        "hermione",
        "sirius"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What book with a yellow cover is in Umbridge's desk drawer at the Ministry of Magic?",
      "answer": "Mudbloods and How to Spot Them",
      "key_words": [
        "mudbloods and how to spot them",
        "yellow book",
        "umbridge",
        "ministry",
        "desk drawer"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion makes the drinker lucky for a period of time?",
      "answer": "Felix Felicis",
      "key_words": [
        "felix felicis",
        "lucky",
        "luck potion",
        "liquid luck",
        "golden"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion is known as the most powerful truth serum?",
      "answer": "Veritaserum",
      "key_words": [
        "veritaserum",
        "truth serum",
        "truth potion",
        "powerful",
        "interrogation"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion restores someone's health after being Petrified?",
      "answer": "Mandrake Restorative Draught",
      "key_words": [
        "mandrake restorative draught",
        "mandrake",
        "petrified",
        "restores",
        "basilisk"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion heals severe injuries like broken bones?",
      "answer": "Skele-Gro",
      "key_words": [
        "skele-gro",
        "skelegro",
        "bones",
        "broken bones",
        "heals",
        "injuries"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion helps with cold and flu symptoms?",
      "answer": "Pepperup Potion",
      "key_words": [
        "pepperup potion",
        "pepperup",
        "cold",
        "flu",
        "symptoms",
        "pepper"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion causes the drinker to fall asleep immediately?",
      "answer": "Draught of Living Death",
      "key_words": [
        "draught of living death",
        "sleep",
        "asleep",
        "immediately",
        "potions class"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion enhances memory?",
      "answer": "Mnemosyne Potion",
      "key_words": [
        "mnemosyne potion",
        "memory",
        "enhances",
        "brain",
        "remembering"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What potion grants temporary protection from fire?",
      "answer": "Fire Protection Potion",
      "key_words": [
        "fire protection potion",
        "fire",
        "protection",
        "temporary",
        "flames"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Amortentia?",
      "answer": "The most powerful love potion",
      "key_words": [
        "amortentia",
        "love potion",
        "most powerful",
        "obsession",
        "attraction"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "category_6": [
    {
      "question": "What memory does Harry draw upon to conjure a Patronus during his lesson with Professor Lupin?",
      "answer": "The memory of his father and mother",
      "key_words": ["Harry", "Patronus", "memory", "father", "mother", "Lupin"]
    },
    {
      "question": "How many lacewing flies does a brewing of Polyjuice Potion require?",
      "answer": "Four – unsiccated ones at that!",
      "key_words": [
        "Polyjuice Potion",
        "lacewing flies",
        "four",
        "4",
        "4 flies",
        "4 lacewing flies",
        "four flies"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Occlumency is used to do what?",
      "answer": "Shield minds from access or influence",
      "key_words": ["Occlumency", "shield mind", "protection"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Hermione use to erase the memories of the Death Eaters that attack her, Harry, and Ron in a café in London?",
      "answer": "Obliviate/Memory Charm",
      "key_words": ["Hermione", "Obliviate", "Memory Charm", "Death Eaters"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the incantation to use to repair the Vanishing Cabinet?",
      "answer": "Harmonia Nectere Passus",
      "key_words": ["Vanishing Cabinet", "repair", "Harmonia Nectere Passus"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the effect of Felix Felicis potion?",
      "answer": "It makes the drinker lucky for a period of time",
      "key_words": ["Felix Felicis", "potion", "effect", "luck"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Gilderoy Lockhart try to use to erase Harry and Ron's memories?",
      "answer": "Obliviate",
      "key_words": ["Gilderoy Lockhart", "spell", "erase memory", "Obliviate"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Hermione Granger conjure to send messages to other members of Dumbledore's Army?",
      "answer": "A Patronus",
      "key_words": [
        "Hermione Granger",
        "Dumbledore's Army",
        "message",
        "Patronus"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What magical creature is a phoenix known for being able to do?",
      "answer": "Rebirth from ashes",
      "key_words": ["phoenix", "creature", "rebirth", "ashes"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the incantation for the Shield Charm?",
      "answer": "Protego",
      "key_words": ["incantation", "Shield Charm", "Protego"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use to disarm opponents?",
      "answer": "Expelliarmus",
      "key_words": ["Harry Potter", "spell", "disarm", "Expelliarmus"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Snape's Patronus?",
      "answer": "A doe",
      "key_words": ["Snape", "Patronus", "doe"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the house-elf that serves the Malfoy family?",
      "answer": "Dobby",
      "key_words": ["house-elf", "Malfoy family", "Dobby"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell causes an object to rise high into the air?",
      "answer": "Alarte Ascendare",
      "key_words": ["spell", "object", "rise", "Alarte Ascendare"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Once cast, which charm creates a positive force that acts as a shield so Dementors feed on it rather than the wizard?",
      "answer": "The Patronus Charm",
      "key_words": [
        "patronus charm",
        "patronus",
        "dementors",
        "shield",
        "positive force",
        "expecto patronum"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the incantation for the spell that reduces solid objects into tiny little pieces?",
      "answer": "Reducto",
      "key_words": [
        "reducto",
        "reduces",
        "solid objects",
        "tiny pieces",
        "blasting curse"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What department at the Ministry of Magic cures Aunt Marge?",
      "answer": "Accidental Magic Reversal Squad",
      "key_words": [
        "accidental magic reversal squad",
        "aunt marge",
        "ministry",
        "department",
        "inflation"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is known as the art of reading tea leaves to predict the future?",
      "answer": "Tessomancy",
      "key_words": [
        "tessomancy",
        "tea leaves",
        "predict future",
        "divination",
        "trelawney"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the incantation for the Summoning Charm?",
      "answer": "Accio",
      "key_words": [
        "accio",
        "summoning charm",
        "summoning",
        "incantation",
        "objects"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry cast to propel him up from the Black Lake when his Gillyweed runs out?",
      "answer": "Ascendio",
      "key_words": [
        "ascendio",
        "black lake",
        "gillyweed",
        "propel",
        "up",
        "triwizard"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is written next to the spell 'Sectumsempra' in Harry's Potions book?",
      "answer": "\"For enemies\"",
      "key_words": [
        "for enemies",
        "sectumsempra",
        "potions book",
        "half-blood prince",
        "snape"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What heals Harry from the Basilisk's venom?",
      "answer": "Phoenix tears",
      "key_words": [
        "phoenix tears",
        "fawkes",
        "basilisk venom",
        "heals",
        "tears"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Dumbledore, what is the most inexhaustible source of magic?",
      "answer": "Words",
      "key_words": [
        "words",
        "dumbledore",
        "inexhaustible",
        "source of magic",
        "language"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Hermione use to free Harry and Ron from the Devil's Snare?",
      "answer": "Lumos Solem",
      "key_words": [
        "lumos solem",
        "devil's snare",
        "devils snare",
        "hermione",
        "light",
        "sun"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell did Harry use to save himself from falling off his broom in his first Quidditch match?",
      "answer": "Arresto Momentum",
      "key_words": [
        "arresto momentum",
        "falling",
        "broom",
        "first quidditch match",
        "hermione"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell produces light from the end of a wand?",
      "answer": "Lumos",
      "key_words": ["lumos", "light", "wand", "illumination", "bright"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell stuns an opponent?",
      "answer": "Stupefy",
      "key_words": ["stupefy", "stunning", "stuns", "opponent", "unconscious"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell binds a target with ropes?",
      "answer": "Incarcerous",
      "key_words": ["incarcerous", "binds", "ropes", "target", "binding"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell disarms an opponent?",
      "answer": "Expelliarmus",
      "key_words": ["expelliarmus", "disarming", "disarms", "wand", "opponent"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell is used to unlock doors?",
      "answer": "Alohomora",
      "key_words": ["alohomora", "unlock", "doors", "locks", "open"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell is used to summon objects?",
      "answer": "Accio",
      "key_words": ["accio", "summon", "objects", "summoning charm", "bring"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell produces a jet of water from the caster's wand?",
      "answer": "Aguamenti",
      "key_words": ["aguamenti", "water", "jet", "wand", "hydro"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell produces a shield?",
      "answer": "Protego",
      "key_words": ["protego", "shield", "protection", "block", "defense"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell levitates objects?",
      "answer": "Wingardium Leviosa",
      "key_words": [
        "wingardium leviosa",
        "levitate",
        "objects",
        "float",
        "feather"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell produces a bright flash of light?",
      "answer": "Lumos",
      "key_words": ["lumos", "bright flash", "light", "flash", "illumination"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell produces a loud bang and sparks?",
      "answer": "Periculum",
      "key_words": ["periculum", "loud bang", "sparks", "red sparks", "signal"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell conjures the Dark Mark?",
      "answer": "Morsmordre",
      "key_words": [
        "morsmordre",
        "dark mark",
        "conjures",
        "death eaters",
        "skull"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell kills instantly?",
      "answer": "Avada Kedavra",
      "key_words": [
        "avada kedavra",
        "killing curse",
        "instantly",
        "death",
        "unforgivable"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell repairs broken objects?",
      "answer": "Reparo",
      "key_words": ["reparo", "repairs", "broken", "objects", "fix"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Lockhart try to use that backfires on him?",
      "answer": "Obliviate",
      "key_words": [
        "obliviate",
        "lockhart",
        "backfires",
        "memory charm",
        "gilderoy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Ron use to knock out a troll?",
      "answer": "Wingardium Leviosa",
      "key_words": ["wingardium leviosa", "ron", "troll", "knock out", "club"]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use against the spiders in the Forbidden Forest?",
      "answer": "Arania Exumai",
      "key_words": [
        "arania exumai",
        "spiders",
        "forbidden forest",
        "aragog",
        "acromantula"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Snape use to heal Draco after Harry uses Sectumsempra?",
      "answer": "Vulnera Sanentur",
      "key_words": [
        "vulnera sanentur",
        "snape",
        "heal",
        "draco",
        "sectumsempra"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What spell does Harry use to reveal that Draco Malfoy is carrying something in his robes?",
      "answer": "Accio",
      "key_words": ["accio", "harry", "draco", "malfoy", "robes", "reveal"]
    }
  ]
}
